<?xml version="1.0"  encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?>
  <modulegroup>
  <name>Forum</name>
  <description>Create and manage an arbitrary number of forums.</description>
  <modules>
    <module type="connector" guid="d7af5f9eee4babcc8271aa2bf606bdcf" name="Connector" class="connector_forum" file="connector_forum.php">Connevtor of the Forum module</module>
    <module type="box" guid="25295fc246600f6f910819e345acc3a7" name="Comments Box" class="actionbox_comments" file="actbox_comments.php">Box that connects to a forum for comments. Used in combination with &quot;Forum Page&quot;</module>
    <module type="box" guid="72452b00cf9e3be09b3e40b82a16299e" name="Last Entries Box" class="actionbox_lastentries" file="actbox_lastentries.php">Box that displays the last entries made in a forum or forum category.</module>
    <module type="box" guid="10dddd13fd77797172fdba277982050f" name="Forum Box" class="actionbox_forum" file="actbox_forum.php">Box displaying a forum. Works just like the forum page, just in a box. Forum boxes can be switched into page comment mode to use them as comment boxes. In this mode for the page, this box is contained in, a forum is created within the category tree when the first comment is written by a user. All other comments for this page become topics of this forum while answers to them are possible as well.</module>
    <module type="page" guid="5d5a8e892c77436f5ffd005175c323b8" name="Forum Page" class="content_forum" file="content_forum.php">Displays a forum or allows users to navigate through forum categories.</module>
    <module type="admin" guid="62ddb02f4d397f55f90bd113f7f2d4cb" name="Forums" class="edmodule_forum" file="edmodule_forum.php" glyph="module-forum.png">Create and edit categories and forums. The administration module enables you to monitor forums and edit forum entries.</module>
    <module type="page" guid="228aa005790e1780bce663d842ad1924" name="Last Entries Page" class="content_forum_lastentries" file="content_forum_lastentries.php">Page that displays the last entries in a forum or forum category.</module>
  </modules>
  <tables>
    <table name="forum">
      This table stores the forums. Each forum does have an integer
      id, a free text description, a title and a reference to a forum category.
      Every forum is contained within one category. Categories may be contained
      in other categories as well. This makes a tree structure. Additionally
      a page_id attribute is stored for each forum, to enable association of
      forums with specific pages.
    </table>
    <table name="forumcategs">
      This table stores the category tree. Each category is identified using
      an integer value, has a reference to the parent category where the
      current category belongs to and a human readable title and description.
      forumcat_path is a list of semicolon separated category ids to allow fast
      search queries.
    </table>
    <table name="forumentries">
      This table stores all entries in all forums. Each entry is identified using
      an integer value and refers to a forum where the specific entry is part of.
      Entries can have a parent or their entry_pid attribute is set to 0. Thus
      entries within a forum that have no parent are called topics, those having
      a parent are called answers. The tree like structure formed this way is called
      a thread. To speed up searching processes each entry does have a redundant
      attribute called entry_path which is a colon seperated list of entry-ids,
      forming the path to the current entry. Each entry has a subject and text
      where text may contain html tags. To enable full-text search another redundant
      attribute called entry_strip exists, where forum entry-texts are stored to,
      after they have been stripped of all html tags. For each entry the author
      is stored as. For security reasons all posts are logged storing the authors
      current IP address.
      If entry_sendanswers equals 1, notification for administrators is enabled.
    </table>
    <table name="forumsubscriptions">
      Stores the thread subscriptions of registered users.
      Only topics can be subscribed currently. (Entries having entry_pid=0)
    </table>
  </tables>
</modulegroup>